Hi, I'm Arthur Noxon, president of Acoustic Sciences.
Right now we're going to talk about how to make an acoustic barrier.
Now the purpose of this barrier is to be inside of a home studio.
And now the second purpose of a barrier is usually to separate one instrument from another instrument, so that the mics associated with recording one instrument aren't picking up bleed from the next door neighbor, these are typically called gobos.
And so now, a gobo is, there's different kinds of gobos, and so the first and most common one would be a sound absorbing gobo.
So this is 2 inch air conditioning duct board.
This is a sound absorbing panel, 2 inches is the minimum thickness that we use in our company.
When you're using a product like this, you have bass isolation, because of the weight, and you have treble isolation, because of the glass.
Now the bass is isolated, but it's reflected back into the area that it came from, because this amount of material is not enough to absorb much bass, 2 inches of fiberglass only absorbs down to about a half an octave below middle C. So a gobo that reflects bass, remember, it keeps the bass inside of the recording space where the bass was coming from, so it causes more bass to be inside the gobo space.
Okay.
This is an interesting version, this is more of a finished product, but it's a form of a gobo.
A hard heavy interior core, but with absorption on both sides.
Now you have an instrument here, and an instrument here, you've got a bass barrier between the instruments, and you have a treble range absorber on either side.
So that is the typical gobo assembly. And in our case, we take a piece of 2 by 4, we make a little notch here, and a little notch here, take a piece of medite, or we can take a piece of hardy board, or backer board, glue it into the notch, and you have a frame with a bass barrier in the middle that's holding it all together, and then you have absorption on either side of it, and then cover it with fabric, staple the fabric on, and you're done.